

Amelia Claire Reiser

750 Barber St. Athens, GA 30601 (405)306-0080

Age: 22 Height: 5'7" Weight: 135 Hair Color: Red

Eye Color: Dark Brown

A classically trained dancer with 18 years of dance training and over 10 years of pre-professional performance experience; an emphasis on classical ballet training, formal contemporary training, and other dance experience ranging from tap, jazz, character, hip-hop, ballroom, and aerial dance. A strong technical background with experience in improvisation and composition allows for adaptability, quick retention of choreography, and a respect and dedication to all aspects of the performing arts world.

Performance Experience

Diavolo Dance Theater, Company B / September 2010

Performed in AWOL.

UGA CORE Concert Dance Company / 2009-2010

Contemporary and Aerial Dance Concert Company

Perpetual Motion Modern Dance, Oklahoma Contemporary Dance Festival / Summer 2009 Contemporary and Trapeze

Senior Exit Dance Concert / 2007-2010

Performed senior student choreography, and choreographed with the University of Georgia **Young Choreographers Series** / 2007-2009

Performed and choreographed with the University of Georgia

Dance Education

University of Georgia Dance Department, Athens GA	2007 – Present	
Ballet I – IV, Contemporary I – IV, Pointe, Pas de Deux, Jazz I – III, Improvisation, Composition,		
Pilates		
University of Oklahoma School of Dance, Norman OKSpring 2	2007, Spring 2009	
Modern technique I-II, Ballroom Dancing I		
Classical Ballet Academy, Norman OK	1991-2007	
Ballet, Pointe, Jazz, Tap, Hip-Hop, Modern		

Festivals

Shen Wei Arts Workshop with Javier Bācá, San Diego Dance Theater, CA	AWinter 2010
Bates Dance Festival, Lewiston, ME	Summer 2010
American Dance Festival Winter Intensive, NYC	Winter 2009

Academic Honors and Awards

University of Georgia Dean's List National Honor Society National Student Leadership Conference	
Education University of Georgia	2007 – Present
GPA: 3.35 University of Oklahoma	2006-2007, Spring 2009

Norman High

GPA: 3.78

Work Experience

Information Desk UGA Tate Student Center, Athens, GA / June 2010 - Present
 Dance instructor Classical Ballet Academy, Norman, OK / 2005-2006, Summer 2009
 Student Gallery Assistant, Jacobson House Native American Art Gallery, Norman, OK / Spring and Summer 2009

Other activities

Dance/USA Member, / 2010 - Present Delta Gamma Sorority / 2007 – Present

Volunteer, Full Plate, food program for homeless shelters, Athens, GA / 2008

Volunteer, Center for Children and Families, family emergency foster care / 2001-2007